

Profile

An experienced Software engineer with over three years of architecture Enterprise and Consumer-based software solutions.

Built functional and scalable web-based solutions utilizing SOLID programming skills and Web Optimization tools.

Supervised and Implemented secure coding strategies for enterprise systems SAAS applications and cloud-based infrastructures.

Employment History

WordPress Developer at Stapek Academy, Ikeja

June 2019 — March 2020

- create and implement WordPress themes and plugins, and handling integrations and regular updates of the CMS using front-end and back-end development skills,
- Designed landing pages for e-commerce, social media websites etc., using Figma.
- Collaborated in Product design sessions.
- Testing, troubleshooting the website and analyzing live website performance

Web developer at Arigo.ng, Lekki

March 2020 — February 2021

- -Developing the front-end of the website, Planning and creating the website architecture
- -Managing back-end tasks like database and server integration
- -Ensured user experience and web application structure aligned appropriately with web development standards and trends.
- Developed unit and e2e tests for applications and test strategies for optimal performance and reliability testing.

Frontend Developer at Twinkle Interactive , Lekki

February 2021 — 2023

- Research, diagnose, troubleshoot, and resolve customer issues in accurately and promptly.
- -Built reusable components for applications in a private NPM Registry on Azure DevOps using React, Storybook, Jest and NPM.
- Manage state optimally with Redux and Optimized web pages for speed and scalability.
- Consumed API Endpoints for all enterprise solutions.
- Developed UI Mock-ups and prototypes that illustrate web application UI and UX.

Details

Lagos, Nigeria, 07036228384 noahssark47@gmail.com

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

React

PHP

CSS

Redux

jQuery

HTML5

Git

JavaScript

WordPress

Team player

Time Management

Critical Thinking

Creative Thinking

Hobbies

Music, Reading, Coding

Education

B. Engr. Mechanical Engineering, Univeristy of Ilorin, Ilorin

October 2010 — October 2015

Frontend Development, Freecode Camp, Virtual

March 2019 — January 2020

Courses

Frontend Development , Freecode

Android Development, Andela and google

January 2020 — January 2021

React.js, Serenze Global

January 2021 — January 2022

Internships

React Web Developer at Serenze Global, Remote

January 2021 — January 2022